thelearningodyssey.com 2016-03-14

# Privacy Policy - Compass Learning

## Privacy Policy

**COMPASSLEARNING RESPECTS YOUR PRIVACY.**  
Please read below to see what personally identifiable information and/or personally identifiable information we may collect and how we may use and share such information.

**PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**  
In connection with your use of certain CompassLearning or Renzulli products or services, such as, CompassLearning Odyssey and Renzulli Learning, we will collect personally identifiable information about you when you or your school provide it to us or if it is collected passively through cookies. We do collect and sometimes share information, such as anonymous statistical or de-identified information, about your visit with companies with which we have partnered. Schools shall have in place a policy to address the use of, and access to, confidential information that identifies a student (“Student Information”) and are responsible for configuring roles based access to Student Information in the CompassLearning Odyssey and Renzulli Learning in accordance with its policy.

CompassLearning shall maintain Student Information for and on behalf of you – in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”), 20 U.S.C. § 1232g(a)(4)(A)(ii), 1232g(b)(1) – for the primary purpose of providing assessment and research services pursuant to this EULA. As between you and CompassLearning, you retain ownership of the Student Information.

We may share Student Information with your school. Teachers, administrators and district administrators can configure reports based on Student Information. These reports can be exported to PDF’s or spreadsheets. We may also share Student Information with researchers or analysts who have agreed in writing to protect the confidentiality of such information in order for them to prepare white papers or analysis regarding the efficacy of our products or services. No white papers or analysis shared publicly would disclose any Student Information. Except solely as allowed by FERPA, authorized by you, provided herein or in the CompassLearning End User License Agreement (together, the “EULA”), we will not sell, lease or provide any third party Student Information we may collect from you except pursuant to a written confidentiality agreement as necessary to make one of our products or services available to you, in connection with a sale or change of control of CompassLearning or any of its assets, or if CompassLearning has reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone damaging, injuring, or interfering with our rights, property, or users.

CompassLearning employees and employees of CompassLearning and its affiliates’ contractors shall be deemed school officials for the purpose of access to Student Information if they have a legitimate interest in maintaining, organizing, or analyzing the data for assessment and research purposes under the EULA. You are responsible for any notices to parents required under FERPA and for providing parents/guardians with an opportunity to inspect and challenge the contents of the student records in question.

In addition, if you are using a module of functionality made available by a third party that is not integrated in a CompassLearning or Renzulli product, including, for example, an assessment tool or a foreign language module, such third party may collect Student Information from you and/or we may share Student Information with such third party, in each case in order for you to receive such service.

**PERSONAL INFORMATION PRACTICES REGARDING CHILDREN**

_What personally identifiable information is collected from children?_  
Through the course of providing access to and use of certain CompassLearning or Renzulli products or services, such as, CompassLearning Odyssey and/or Renzulli Learning, we may collect or have access to: your name, grade level, student school ID, user name, password, gender, ethnicity, race, whether you have special needs, certain sociological/economic factors regarding you that may impact your learning, factors relating to your scholastic performance, status and/or enrollment status, log domain names, IP address, a processor or device serial number, geolocation data, and/or a unique device identifier. CompassLearning employees and employees of CompassLearning and its affiliates’ contractors shall be deemed school officials for the purpose of access to personally identifiable information if they have a legitimate interest in maintaining, organizing, or analyzing the data for assessment and research purposes under the EULA. You are responsible for any notices to parents required under COPPA and for providing parents/guardians with an opportunity to inspect and correct personally identifiable information.

_How is this personally identifiable information used?_  
Any personally identifiable information that is collected is used to customize your learning experience, to improve our services, to assess and/or communicate your performance with you and/or your school, as applicable.

_With whom do we share personally identifiable information collected from children?_  
We may share your personally identifiable information with your school. Teachers, administrators and district administrators can configure reports based on such information. These reports can be exported to PDF’s or spreadsheets. We may also share personally identifiable information with researchers or analysts who have agreed in writing to protect the confidentiality of such information in order for them to prepare white papers or analysis regarding the efficacy of our products or services. No white papers or analysis shared publicly would disclose any Student Information. In addition, if you are using a module of functionality made available by a third party that is not integrated in a CompassLearning or Renzulli product, including, for example, an assessment tool or a foreign language module, such third party may collect personally identifiable information from you and/or we may share personally identifiable information with such third party, in each case in order for you to receive such service. Except solely as provided herein, we will not sell, lease or provide any third party personally identifiable information collected from children under 13 except as necessary pursuant to a written confidentiality agreement to make one of our products or services available to such child, in connection with a sale or change of control of CompassLearning or any of its assets, or if CompassLearning has reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone damaging, injuring, or interfering with our rights, property, or users.

If you request that your information be removed or if we no longer need to store it, we will securely destroy, erase, or make the information anonymous or request that your school securely destroy, erase, or make the information anonymous.

**PRIOR NOTICE AND CONSENT TO COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION FROM** **CHILDREN UNDER 13**  
We rely upon consent from schools instead of parents for use by their students of our products and services, including, without limitation, providing parents/guardians with an opportunity to inspect and challenge the contents of the student records in question. We provide information regarding our practices concerning the collection, use, and disclosure of personally identifiable information to such schools and to you. You acknowledge that CompassLearning and its affiliates (and their partners) may have access to Student Information. CompassLearning employees and employees of CompassLearning and its affiliates’ contractors shall be deemed school officials for the purpose of access to personally identifiable information derived from Student Information only if they have a legitimate interest in maintaining, organizing, or analyzing the data for assessment and research purposes under this EULA.

**COOKIES**  
If you are accessing software hosted by CompassLearning, CompassLearning may gather and maintain a record of your internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), your referring and/or exit pages, operating system, a date/time stamp and clickstream data. CompassLearning may use HTML cookies to track information about visitors to Compass sites so that we may understand and improve such sites. A cookie is a small data file that is stored on your computer for record-keeping purposes. CompassLearning may also link the information that we store in cookies to the personally identifiable information you submit for various purposes such as understanding how you use content and which of its features are most used by you in order to improve your educational experience. You need to have cookies enabled to use the CompassLearning products. CompassLearning may use Adobe Flash cookies (and/or similar applications) to remember settings, preferences and usage similar to browser cookies but these are managed through a different interface than the one provided by your web browser. CompassLearning may employ Adobe Flash cookies to provide special content such as video clips or animation or to provide you with customized content or remember the last page you visited, keep track of preferences you specify while you are using our products.

**OPTING-OUT, CORRECTIONS AND CANCELLATIONS**  
Upon request, CompassLearning will or will request that the applicable school: a) remove you and your personally identifiable information and/or personally identifiable information from our database, thereby canceling your registration for use of our products and services; b) correct personally identifiable information that you state is erroneous. To request a correction or cancellation, contact successteam@compasslearning.com. Opting out means you will no longer receive unsolicited email or other contact generated by your registration at https://www.compasslearning.com.

**SECURITY**  
If we are hosting CompassLearning or Renzulli products or services, we review our Web security on a regular basis. Information collected from users of our products or services is stored on databases and other servers kept in secure locations under the custody and control of CompassLearning or its designees. CompassLearning also uses technologies and processes, such as encryption, access control procedures, and network firewalls that are designed to protect such servers. CompassLearning makes commercially reasonable efforts to protect such information and to limit its use and disclosure but cannot guarantee that such efforts will be successful. Please note that sending data over the Internet is never completely secure. Although we will endeavor to fully protect your information, we cannot guarantee the security of the data you transmit to us or allow us to collect, and you do so at your own risk.

**OTHER SITES**  
CompassLearning products may contain links to other carefully chosen sites. However, CompassLearning cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. You should review the privacy policy of each specific site.

**HOSTING BY THIRD PARTIES**  
If we are licensing CompassLearning or Renzulli products on an enterprise basis to be hosted by a school or its designee, we not providing and are not responsible for any system security. In addition, the school that is hosting such product may collect different information than is indicated here. Consult such school. In addition, we are not responsible for how this information we may share with your school may be used or disclosed by such school.

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**  
We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy at any time. If our policy changes, we will post a notice on our site.

**ACCOUNTABILITY**  
We have a Privacy Officer for CompassLearning who is accountable for our site’s compliance to our privacy policy. If you have any questions about our policy, contact us at:

Privacy Officer  
203 Colorado Street  
Austin TX 78701  
512.492.6918  
AUS-Legal@compasslearning.com

_Revised: May 6, 2014_
